The next aggregate we are going to use is
the COUNT aggregate. COUNT just shows the
number of records for each item in a group. In
this query, we already have aggregates for SUM,
MIN, and MAX, and I will just add
another for a count of subtotals
for each salesperson. I will copy
and paste an existing aggregate
and then change this aggregate to COUNT,
change the alias to 'Total number of Sales',
and execute this. Now we see the number
of orders each salesperson has achieved.
Before we get to any other aggregates, let's
see if we can sort based on an aggregate. I will
attempt to add an ORDER BY clause to the end of
this query to sort this list on the subtotal count
in descending order. I will run this, and indeed
it worked. The next aggregate has a keyword that
may differ depending upon the exact version
of SQL you are using. This aggregate is the
AVERAGE aggregate. In some versions of SQL,
AVG is the keyword to use, as it is here for
Microsoft SQL Server. I will paste another copy
of the aggregate I copied earlier to this query,
change the keyword to AVG to get an
average subtotal for each salesperson,
make sure I have a comma at the end of the
COUNT aggregate, and then execute this query.
Look at all the aggregates we have
now: SUM, MIN, MAX, COUNT, and AVERAGE.